你昨晚见着那个小妞了吗
You meet up with that baby last night?
-没错  -见着了?  又没睡觉?
- Yeah. - Yeah? No sleep again?
没有  绝不睡觉  我们向来如此
Never. No sleep, baby. That's how we do it.
主厨
Chef? Chef?
摸下他的脉搏
Check his pulse.
-什么碎了  -一只破杯子
- What broke? - A stupid glass.
记得提醒我去买些"好"杯子
Remind me to get smarter glasses.
但我觉得问题不在于杯子的好坏
Somehow I feel that the glass is not quite the problem.
蕾西一家还有其他几个朋友
I got invited to the Hamptons with Lacey's family
-邀请我去汉普顿玩儿  -那不挺有趣的嘛
- and a couple of other friends. - Well, that sounds like fun.
你怎么看上去  好似《幸存者》里有人被投票淘汰出岛了
So why do you look like someone who just got voted off the island?
下周就要大学预修课考试了
AP tests are next week,
所以整个周末我都得在家看书
so I really need to study all weekend.
但我又真的很想去汉普顿
But I really want to go to the Hamptons.
工作与玩乐是永恒的两难抉择
The eternal struggle between work and play.
窍门是  你长大后
The trick is, when you grow up,
找个"工作即玩乐"的工作
find work that feels like play.
说到工作
Speaking of work...
你为什么这么早就起床整装待发了
What are you doing up and dressed so early?
不为什么  我就是觉得应该趁早拥抱新的一天
Oh, no reason. Just thought I'd get an early start to my day.
拜拜
Bye.
好了  那么  我们明晚见吧
All right. So, um, I'll see you tomorrow night?
-好啊  就这样吧  -好的
- Yeah. Good. Okay. - Okay.
回见
See ya.
戴明跑到我们的茶水间里干嘛
What's Demming doing in our break room?
楼下的咖啡有什么不妥吗
Is there something wrong with the coffee downstairs?
我们的咖啡机可是你买的  卡塞尔
Well, you're the one who bought us the cappuccino machine, Castle.
没错  但我是买给凶案组的
Yes, but I bought it for homicide
不是买给整个警局的
not the entire precinct.
-明晚有什么安排  -什么
- What's tomorrow night? - What?
汤姆想问我明晚
Oh, Tom was wondering if
有没有兴趣小聚一下
I wanted to get together tomorrow night.
怎么了  有什么问题吗
Why? Is that a problem?
我能有什么问题
Why would I have a problem with that?
抱歉
Excuse me.
好的  马上过去
Okay. Be right there.
汤姆
Tom.
凶案发生在Q3
The murder is at Q3?
这家店开业才三个月
This place has only been open three months.
我连个餐位都订不到
I can't even get a reservation here.
在这吃上一顿我死都值了
I've been dying to eat here.
事实证明  你不是唯一一个想死在这儿的
Well, evidently, you're not the only one.
-死者在哪  -厨房里
- Where are we?  - In the kitchen.
死者名叫巴尔萨扎·伍尔夫
Victim's name is Balthazar Wolf.
是这里的主厨
He's the head chef here.
"大恶人伍尔夫"吗  《厨房大战》第六季的冠军
Big bad Wolf? Winner of "Kitchen Wars," Season 6?
就是他了
I know. Right?
不是吧  我再也尝不到他的鹅肝三明治了
Aw, man. I never got to taste his foie gras sandwich.
今早发现他的是糕点师
He was found this morning by the pastry chef--
斯派克·雷登哈尔
Spike Ridenhauer--
还有一位洗碗工  胡安·科斯塔
and one of the dishwashers-- Juan Costa.
卡塞尔  别动
Castle, stop!
你没看到尸体周围的橙色圆锥物吗
D-do you not see the little orange cones around the body?
那真是他的手吗
Is that actually his hand?
那是L-N-2造成的
That's the effect of L-N-2...
就是我们平常所说的液氮
Commonly known as liquid nitrogen,
一种制冷剂
a cryogenic refrigerant.
可以在接触瞬间冻住一切物品
It instantly freezes anything it comes in touch with,
包括伍尔夫先生  这导致他像玻璃一样易碎
including Mr. Wolf-- made him fragile as glass.
这真是由内而外的酷毙了
This is both literally and figuratively cool.
伍尔夫一直推崇分子美食学
Uh, Wolf was a follower of molecular gastronomy.
就是用科学的方法去操作...
It's using the science to manipulate the...
你们都不关心这些
And you don't care.
这东西通常是很安全的
It's usually pretty safe
除非某人把它倒在你身上
unless someone dumps it on you.
死亡时间呢
Time of death?
一切常用的指示物
Well, all our normal indicators...
都被液氮污染了
are contaminated by the L-N-2.
我回到停尸房之后再看看有什么办法
I'll see what I can do once I get to the morgue.
但是我们得先等他解冻一会
But, uh, we're gonna have to let him thaw a bit
然后才能移动尸体
before we can move him.
-看上去有挣扎的痕迹  -是抢劫吗
- Looks like there was a struggle.  - Robbery?
不是  没有强闯的迹象  也没有丢东西
No, no sign of forced entry, nothing's missing.
根据雷登哈尔先生和科斯塔先生所说
According to Mr. Ridenhauer and Mr. Costa here,
死者在其他人都离开餐厅后  还一直留在这
our victim stayed at the restaurant long after everyone else had left.
那是什么时候
And what time was that?
差不多十一点
It was around 11:00.
一位客人特别订制了一个蛋糕
One of our clients had special ordered a cake,
于是伍尔夫留下来把蛋糕做完
and Wolf stayed behind to finish it up.
你不是糕点师吗
Aren't you the pastry chef?
没错  但我可不会陪着伍尔夫一起疯
Yeah, but I don't do crazy stuff like Wolf does.
我只是做了垫子形状的底座
I just, uh, I made the cushion,
然后他刻了这个皇冠
and he sculpted the crown,
还有这颗心和珠宝
uh, the heart and the jewels.
也许这就是他把旋转蒸发器
That's probably why he had the rotary
和液氮拿出来的原因
evaporator out and the liquid nitrogen.
好的  等帕穆特把尸体弄走之后
All right, after Perlmutter gets the body out,
让鉴证小组过来
I'm gonna want CSU to come in
搜集一下现场的纤维和指纹
and sweep for fibers and prints.
-好的  -贝克特  餐厅老板来了
- Yeah, yeah.  - Yo, Beckett. The owner's here.
-说是发生了一起意外  -麦蒂森
- Say there's been an accident.  - Madison?
小贝? 你来这里干嘛呢
Becks? What are you doing here?
我现在是凶杀案探长
I'm a homicide detective.
-这也太扯了吧  -我也觉得
- Shut the front door. - I know.
想不到吧
I-I know, right?
咱俩的重聚方式可真够糟糕的
What a messed up way for us to reconnect.
麦蒂森·凯勒  这位是理查德·卡塞尔
Madison Queller, this is Richard Castle.
-你好  -你好  请叫我里克
- Hi.  - Hi. Please call me Rick.
-你们俩是怎么认识的  -高中同学
- How do you two know each other?  -High school.
九年级法语班
Ninth grade French.
想不到当年最离经叛道的家伙
I can't believe the biggest scofflaw
现在变成了警察
at stuy became a cop.
没错
Yeah.
我需要餐厅所有员工的联系资料
So I'm gonna need contact information for all the restaurant staff.
不是吧  小贝  你觉得是餐厅内部人干的吗
Come on, Becks. You think somebody here might have done it?
没有强闯的迹象  通常表明凶手
You know, no forced entry usually means that the killer
要么认识厨师  要么有餐厅钥匙
either knew the chef or was someone who had keys.
所以我需要所有人的不在场证明
So I'm gonna need alibis from everyone,
包括你的
including you.
-抱歉  -不不  我理解的
- Sorry.  - No. No, I, uh... I understand.
我去参加聚会直到凌晨
I was at a party until the wee hours.
很多人都见到我了
Lots of people saw me.
那你知道伍尔夫有什么仇人吗
Now did you know if Wolf had any enemies,
有没有什么想伤害他的人
anyone that wanted to do him harm?
他是个让所有人又爱又恨的家伙
He was the bad boy America loved to hate.
我当时是嘉宾评委  我们就这么认识的
I was a guest judge. That's how we met.
说真的  你从没听过《厨房大战》吗
Seriously? You never heard of "Kitchen Wars"?
没有  我很少有时间看电视
No. I don't really get a lot of time to watch tv.
这句话竟然出自一个曾花上好几个小时
This from the girl who'd spend hours
看《救命下课铃》重播的女孩之口
watching "Saved By The Bell" reruns?
真的啊
Really?
她还曾花上那么长时间做过什么
What else did she spend hours doing?
卡塞尔  这里是犯罪现场
Castle, real crime scene.
不是悬疑小说家的调查时间  好不
not mystery writer research time, okay?
你最近有发现伍尔夫有什么异常吗
Did you notice anything unusual about Wolf lately?
任何事情
Anything at all.
确实有一件事
There was one thing.
伍尔夫做起事来马不停蹄的
Wolf usually worked nonstop.
你根本没办法把他从厨房里拖出来
You couldn't tear him away from the kitchen.
但最近几周
But for the last couple of weeks,
他都会在三点的时候消失
he'd disappear around 3:00,
然后五点回来刚好赶上准备工作
and come back just in time to prep at 5:00.
他有说他去哪了吗
Did he say where he was going?
没有  他说是私事
No. He said it was personal.
伙计们  有发现
Hey, guys. I found something.
洗碗工胡安是昨晚最后一个离开这里的
Juan the dishwasher was the last one here last night,
他发誓他洗完了所有碟子
and he swears he finished every single dish.
两个脏碗  两根汤勺  还有一个汤锅
Two dirty bowls, two spoons and a soup pot?
看起来伍尔夫深夜有人作伴
Looks like Wolf had some late-night company.
是爆米花羹  这是多明戈的招牌菜
It's popcorn soup. It's Domingo's specialty.
-多明戈  -我们的备菜厨师
- Domingo?  - Our line chef.
他一定是在所有人离开以后回来过
He must have come back after everybody left.
也就是说  他是伍尔夫生前见到的最后一个人
That means he's the last one to have seen Wolf alive.
-你有他的地址吗  -当然
- Do you have an address? - Of course.
找到多明戈  弄清楚为什么
All right, track down Domingo and see
他那么晚还在这里  以及他看到了什么
why he was here so late and what he saw.
我还需要伍尔夫亲属的联系方式
I'll also need the contact info for Wolf's next of kin.
高中好友  是吧
High school friend, huh?
我敢说她一定知道你不少糗事
I bet she knows where all your bodies are buried.
你大可尽情八卦  卡塞尔
You can dig all you want, Castle.
她绝对不会爆我料的
My secrets are safe with her.
你怎么这么肯定
How can you be sure?
因为不管她手里掌握了我什么料
Because whatever she knows about me,
我掌握的她的料都更猛
I know worse about her.
我们以前经常出去玩  一大堆人
We used to hang out, big group of us,
玩得很爽
had a good time.
那么...什么叫很爽
And... what's a good time?
如果你现在还不知道什么叫爽
Well, if you don't know by now,
那你这辈子都甭想知道了
I'm sure it's too late to show you one.
这是伍尔夫的紧急联系人
Here's Wolf's emergency contact--
大卫·尼克莱斯
David Nicolaides.
伍尔夫没有什么真正意义上的家人
Wolf didn't have any real family.
他童年的大部分时光
He spent most of his childhood
都辗转于不同的领养家庭
in and out of foster homes,
所以我们才会被列为亲属
which is why we're listed as, uh, next of kin.
我和我的女友茜茜莉是他最亲近的人了
My girlfriend Cecily and I are about as close as it gets.
他们俩情同手足
They were like brothers.
-你们认识多久了  -十几岁就认识了
- How long did you know each other?  - Since our teens.
我爸爸给他份工作  在我家餐馆里打扫卫生
My dad gave him a job in our restaurant as a busboy,
当时他刚从少管所里出来
Uh, when he got out of juvie.
之后没多久
It didn't take long to tell
我们就发现他在烹饪方面颇有天赋
that he had a real gift for food.
从此他就好像我的家人一样
Been like family ever since.
你知道他有什么仇家吗
Did he have any enemies that you know of?
他在节目里一直以坏小子形象示人
He had a bad-boy image from the show,
但其实他是个好人
but he was actually sweet.
在《厨房大战》中取胜
Winning "Kitchen Wars"
一定对他意义重大吧
must have been huge for him.
他当时是什么反应
How was he handling it?
他很爱这种生活  名利双收
He loved it-- the fame, the fortune.
这都是他一直以来所梦想的  除了...
It was everything he ever dreamed of, e-except...
除了什么
Except what?
我想他可能经济方面遇到了点困难
I-I think he might have had some financial troubles.
什么意思
What do you mean?
当我爸爸几个月前去世时
When my dad passed away a few months back,
他把餐馆留给了我和伍尔夫
he left his restaurant to Wolf and me.
当然不是Q3那种高级餐厅
It was nothing fancy like Q3.
那只是皇后区的一个小饭店
It was just a little diner in queens.
但是两个星期前
But about two weeks ago,
他来找我  问我能不能买下他的股份
he came to me asking if I would buy him out.
我试着劝服他
I tried to talk him out of it.
我甚至告诉他我可以借钱给他
I even told him that I would loan him the money,
但他拒绝了
but he refused.
最后  我就买下了他的那份
And in the end, I gave in and I bought out his share.
-多少钱买下的  -四万
- For how much?  - $40,000.
他不是在《厨房大战》里赢了一大笔钱吗
Didn't he just win a lot of money on "Kitchen Wars"?
他把那笔钱全部投入新餐厅了
Well, he put it all into the new restaurant.
我曾劝他留下一点钱
I tried to tell him to hold some of it back,
但他属于那种孤注一掷的人
but he was an all-or-nothing kind of guy.
詹妮弗  伍尔夫,
Jennifer, Wolf,
我们给你们的菜肴打好分了
we've scored your dishes,
虽然结果很相近
and although it was very close,
巴尔萨扎·伍尔夫
Balthazar Wolf,
你是《厨房大战纽约站》的冠军
you're the winner of "Kitchen Wars, New York!"
看看他的脸
Look at his face.
看到他多高兴没?
See how happy he is?
他全然不知八个月后  他会丧命
He had no idea in eight months, he'd be dead.
拿到了银行的搜查令
Well, the bank has the warrant,
几小时后我们就知道他的经济状况了
so we should have his financials in a couple of hours.
如果他有什么金钱方面的问题  我们会发现的
If he was having money troubles, we'll find out.
午夜汤点师那边有什么进展吗
Hey, how'd it go with the late-night soup maker?
找到他没
You guys find him?
我们很快就找到他了
Oh, we found him all right.
他当时正在机场排队
In line at the airport
箱子里揣着五千块现金
with $5,000 cash in his suitcase
还有一张去厄瓜多尔的单程票
and a one-way ticket to Ecuador.
逃出国境简直就是变相承认自己的罪名嘛
Nothing says "I'm guilty" like an attempt to flee the country.
下次你想把人冻成冰棍的时候
The next time you decide to go all Mr. Freeze on someone,
千万记得不要留下任何痕迹
you should really clean up after yourself.
我们在水池里发现了你的碗
We found your bowls in the sink.
我不懂你在说什么
I don't understand.
我们发现你带着行李箱
We found you with a packed suitcase,
揣着去厄瓜多尔的单程机票  还有五千现金
plane tickets to Ecuador and $5,000 in cash.
这不算有罪吧
That is not a crime.
我有护照的
I have a passport.
你用此来从一桩谋杀案中脱身
Which you were using to flee a murder.
谋杀?  你以为我杀了谁
Murder? Who do you think I killed?
你那戴着厨师帽的头儿
Your boss in the big white hat.
伍尔夫?
Wolf?
伍尔夫死了? 怎么死的
Wolf's dead? how?
维多戈先生  坐下
Mr. Verdugo, sit down.
我没杀任何人
I did not kill anyone.
我们知道你昨晚去找他了
We know you came to see him last night.
没错  我昨晚回了餐厅一趟
Yes. I came back to the restaurant last night.
我的妹妹在厄瓜多尔
My sister, she's in Ecuador.
她病的很重  需要做手术
She's very sick. She needs surgery.
我去问主厨能不能让我回家一趟
I came to ask Chef if can go home.
五千块不是一笔小数目
$5,000 is a lot of money.
你从哪弄到的钱
Where did you get it from?
伍尔夫主厨给我的  用来给我妹妹做手术
Chef Wolf gave it to me for my sister's operation.
我说他这是疯了  但是他坚持把钱给我
Told him he was crazy, but he insisted.
他说  回去照顾你妹妹吧
He said, "go take care of your sister."
五年了  我一直和伍尔夫一起工作
Look, five years, I've worked with Wolf.
他是我的朋友
He's my friend.
我没有杀他
I didn't kill him.
他这么巧就有五千现金在身上
And he just happened to have 5 grand dollar.
没错  在他的背包里
Yes, in his backpack.
我答应会还给他的
Look, I promised to pay him back.
他在背包里放了那么多钱吗
He had that much money in a backpack?
是的  还有更多呢  很多
Yeah, he had more, a lot more.
我告诉他不应该带那么多现金
Look, I told him he shouldn't carry so much cash.
他会被...
He could get...
杀掉的
Killed.
凶案现场没有背包
There was no backpack at the scene.
也许被那位气冲冲的女士偷走了
Maybe that angry lady stole it.
-也许是她杀的伍尔夫  -哪个气冲冲的女士
- Maybe she's the one who killed Wolf. - What angry lady?
-他的一个女友  她来了我就离开了  -何时
- One of his girlfriends. I left when she came. - When?
过了午夜  大约在零点四十五
After midnight, like around 12:45.
-知道她的名字吗  -不知道
- Do you know her name? - No.
但是她总是到餐厅来
But she came into the restaurant all the time.
能描述她的长相吗
Can you describe her?
厨房的员工确认
So the kitchen staff confirms
伍尔夫昨天的确带着背包
that Wolf did have a backpack with him yesterday,
他们之所以注意到
and the only reason that they noticed it
是因为他通常不背包
is because he didn't usually carry one.
这么说多明戈说了实话
So Domingo was telling the truth.
背包存在这个事实
Well, just because the backpack exists
并不意味着他的供词完全可信
doesn't mean that the rest of his story is credible.
是啊  但是关于钱的那部分是真的
No, but he's telling the truth about the money.
伍尔夫的财政情况调出来了
Wolf's financials came in.
近六个月
There's nothing out of the ordinary
没有异常  但是两周前
over the last six months, but then--bam--two weeks ago,
他从他的户头将全部存款取出
he withdraws all his savings from his checking account.
-一万五千美元  -两周前
- $15,000. - 2 weeks ago?
正是那个时候伍尔夫请求
That's about the time that Wolf
他的义兄大卫买下他的股份
asked his foster brother David to buy his share.
支票刚兑现
Yeah, and as soon as that check cleared,
他就取出了那四万美元的现金
he withdrew that $40,000 in cash.
就在他死亡当天
On the day he was killed.
一个人要四万现金干什么
Why would someone need $40,000 in cash?
肯定是违法的事情
Well, nothing legal.
麦蒂森说他每天下午三点到五点
You know, Madison said that he would disappear every day
都会不见人影
between 3:00 and 5:00 pm.
也许他去的地方和这笔钱有关
Maybe where he went had something to do with the money.
你们再去和厨房员工核实一下
Why don't you guys talk to the kitchen staff again?
再查一查他的信用卡消费收据
And let's look into his credit card receipts.
也许我们可以弄清他去了哪里
Maybe we can figure out where he was going.
电话记录方面有什么消息
And where are we on the phone records?
手机卡在冷冻过程中坏掉了
Oh, the sim card was damaged from the freezing.
技术人员在努力还原数据
Tech's seeing what they can salvage.
我们向通讯公司递交了通话记录的传票
And we subpoenaed his phone records from the provider.
还在等待回复
We're waiting on those.
她看起来很可疑
She looks kinda sketchy to me.
她是桑德拉
That's Sandra.
-她和她丈夫每周六都来  -丈夫
- She and her husband are in every Saturday. - Husband?
是啊
Yeah.
多明戈暗示伍尔夫和她有感情瓜葛
Domingo hinted at a romantic relationship.
这肯定违反了好几条卫生管理条例
Which has to violate several health codes.
-记得他们的姓氏吗  -不记得
- Do you remember their last name? - No, no.
但是她的信息应该在预定簿上
But her information should be in the reservation book.
你怎么样
How you holding up?
还很震惊  不过没有时间难过
I'm still reeling, and I have no time to grieve.
伍尔夫是个朋友  但不管怎样
Wolf was a friend, but like it or not,
我得面试代替他的主厨
I have to interview replacement chefs.
我还没有找到伍尔夫做的蛋糕的收据
I still haven't found that customer slip
不知道给谁订做的  明晚还要参加在
for that cake Wolf was making, and I have this charity event
雷克·迪斯普利托[著名厨师]的餐厅举行的慈善晚宴
tomorrow night at Rocco Dispirito's.
要是我没出现
If I don't show up,
大家会认为伍尔夫的死意味着Q3的终结
people will think wolf's death means the death of Q3.
也许你可以和我一起去
Hey, maybe you should come with me.
我需要一些精神上的支持
I could use the moral support,
或许我们能叙叙旧
and maybe we can catch up on old times.
我很想去  只是我有安排了
You know, I would love to. It's just, I have something.
安排
"Something"?
我可以提供精神上的支持
You know, I'm available for moral support.
我一直想去雷克的新餐厅试试
And I've been dying to try out Rocco's new place.
一位迷人的健谈者  再好不过了
A charming raconteur. That's just what the doctor ordered.
谢谢你  里克
Thank you, Rick.
-除非你有异议  -完全没问题
- Unless that's a problem. - No, not a problem.
找到了
Oh, here it is.
桑德拉·迈尔斯
Sandra Meyers.
你和伍尔夫之间的
What was the exact nature
关系到底是什么样的
of your relationship with Wolf?
食物让我兴奋
Food turns me on.
不是当做情趣玩具  是烹饪给身体带来的快感
Not as a sex toy, but the sensual act of cooking.
当我在《厨房大战》看到伍尔夫时
And when I saw Wolf on "Kitchen Wars,"
看到他对食材的热情  我被吸引了
how passionate he was with his ingredients, I fell in lust.
Q3刚刚开张  我和我丈夫就去捧场了
My husband and I were the first through the doors when Q3 opened.
当伍尔夫来关照用餐情况时
And when Wolf came by to check on our meal,
我把电话号码递给了他
I slipped him my number.
你们总是在餐厅发生关系吗
Did you always have sex in the restaurant?
当然  厨房是伍尔夫如鱼得水的地方
Well, Wolf did his best work in the kitchen.
你丈夫从来没有怀疑过吗
And your husband never suspected?
他不在急诊室工作的晚上
When he's not working nights at the E.R.,
他会吃安眠药昏睡过去
he's conked out on sleeping pills.
即使我在客厅拍A片  他也不会知道
I could shoot porn in my living room, he'd have no idea.
你会告诉我丈夫吗
Are you gonna tell my husband?
你是谋杀调查的头号嫌疑人
You're the primary suspect in a murder investigation.
你的丈夫  可不是你最该担心的
Your husband is the least of your worries.
那晚发生了什么  桑德拉
So what happened that night, Sandra?
-性变得死气沉沉了  -没有性
- The sex turn deadly? - No, there was no sex.
两周前  伍尔夫突然给我打电话
Two weeks ago, Wolf called me out of the blue
说我们之间结束了
to tell me we were through.
-两周前  -我给他打电话
- Two weeks. - I tried calling him,
但是他没有打回来
but he wouldn't call me back.
所以我就去餐厅看看怎么回事
So I went to the restaurant last night to find out why.
然后呢
And?
他说他不想再鬼混了
He said he was done screwing around,
他说是成熟的时候了  翻开新的一页
that it was time to grow up, turn over a new damn leaf.
这样做显然让你很生气
And that clearly made you angry.
当然
Sure.
但是我没杀他
But I didn't kill him.
迈尔斯太太  你经常出轨
Mrs Meyers, you cheat on your husband on a regular basis.
我们为什么要相信你
Why should we believe you?
问问我大楼的门卫
Ask the doorman at my building.
一点半以前我就回去了
I was back before 1:30.
我一点十五离开的时候  伍尔夫还活着
When I left the restaurant at 1:15, Wolf was alive.
门卫确认了迈尔斯太太的证词
Doorman confirms Mrs. Meyers' story,
医院也确认迈尔斯医生
and the hospital has Dr. Meyers logged
当晚登记在值夜班
as working the graveyard shift.
那位说谎出轨的妻子说了真话
Well, our lying, cheating wife was telling the truth.
在我们确认伍尔夫死亡时间之前
Yeah, but until we figure out Wolf's time of death,
她依然是头号嫌疑人
she's still our best suspect.
我调查了伍尔夫每天失踪的去向
So I ran down Wolf's daily disappearance.
他的信用卡显示
His credit card records
过去几周每天他都会
show a charge at Cafe Rex
在三点四十五在雷克斯咖啡馆消费
every day the last couple of weeks around 3:45.
雷克斯咖啡馆  那是在七十区第二街上
Cafe Rex? That's on 2nd in the 70's.
伍尔夫在那做什么
What was Wolf doing there?
你们去那里查一查
Why don't you guys head up
他是不是和别人碰面
and see if he was meeting with anyone?
好的  我们马上去
Okay. We'll be right there.
走吧  帕穆特有发现
Come on. Perlmutter found something.
尸体怎么样了
How's our corpse-sicle?
融化的不错
Thawing nicely.
尽管有显而易见的难度
Uh, in spite of the obvious challenges,
我还是找到了足够未受影响的组织
I found enough unaffected tissue to narrow time of death
将死亡时间定于凌晨两点到四点
to between 2:00 and 4:00 a.m.
这样就排除多明戈和迈尔斯太太的嫌疑了
Well, that knocks out both Domingo and Mrs. Meyers.
我们用发热灯照射他的身体时
Now once we got him under the heat lamps,
一些瘀伤便开始显现
some bruising began to present.
首先
Uh, first...
在他的后背和腿部有很明显的
there were significant contusions
挫伤伤痕
along his back and legs.
看起来是很严重的殴打
Wow. This looks like a pretty bad beating.
是在他被杀的那晚发生的吗
Did this happen the night of the murder?
这些伤痕至少有两周了
Uh, these bruises are at least two weeks old.
身上有瘀伤  带着四万美元现金
Bruising on the body, $40,000 in cash...
把餐馆的股份卖给了他义兄
Sold his shares in the diner to his foster brother...
都是在这两周发生的
All within the same 2-week time span.
我在他头部发现一处新伤
I also found a fresh bruise
就在他被冷冻之前被打伤的
from a blow he suffered just before he was frozen.
我看过了鉴证组在现场拍的照片
I went through the crime scene photos from CSU,
伤口的痕迹
and the bruise pattern
与其中一个物品的形状吻合
matches one of the objects from the kitchen.
旋转蒸发器
Rotary evaporator.
是主厨用来蒸馏和提炼...
It's a tool that chefs use to distill and extract flavors from...
看来你们还是不关心
and again, you don't care.
蒸发器主体上没有找到指纹
Yeah, we didn't find any prints on the body of the appliance,
但在破碎的玻璃管上找到了部分指纹
but there were some partials on its shattered glass tube.
实验室的人
Now the guys in the lab
将碎片拼起来  得到了一个可用的指纹
were able to humpty-dumpty together a usable print.
餐厅员工中没有匹配者
Didn't match any of the restaurant employees,
但在指纹识别系统中  查到一个匹配者
but when they ran it through AFIS, they got a hit.
-詹妮弗·王  -不会吧
- Jennifer Wong.  - No.
詹妮弗·王是谁
Who's Jennifer Wong?
你知道我要用牛肉
You knew I was using the veal, so you went
你就到肉铺将所有牛肉买光
straight to the butcher and bought everything he had.
你以为我会在意搞阴谋破坏吗
You think I care about sabotaging you?
我一只手绑在背后
I can cook you off the show
也能赢你
with one hand tied behind my back.
你输了是因为你只是用脑烹饪
You lost because you cook with your head.
我是用心烹饪
I cook with my soul.
他说谎  他偷了我的秘方
He's a liar. He stole that recipe from me.
我对天发誓  如果伍尔夫赢了
I swear to god, if Wolf wins,
我就宰了那婊子养的
I'm gonna kill that son of a bitch.
他偷了我的秘方
He stole that recipe from me.
我对天发誓  如果伍尔夫赢了
I swear to god, if Wolf wins,
我就宰了那婊子养的
I'm gonna kill that son of a bitch.
听起来你跟伍尔夫先生有深仇大恨啊
Sounds like you and Mr. Wolf had quite the rivalry.
-那又怎样  -得了
- What about it?  - Oh, come on.
眼睁睁地看着他拿走10万美金大奖
It had to be difficult, watching him walk away
肯定不好受
with that $100,000 prize.
更别提这名声威望
Not to mention the publicity and fame
大大帮助了他的事业
that catapulted his career.
不难相信过去几个月
And it's not hard to believe that the resentment
仇恨渐渐滋生
was building up over the past couple of months
直到压力把你推向极端
until the pressure finally put you over the edge.
等等  你认为我杀了他
Wait. You think I killed him?
伍尔夫和我的敌对关系
That rivalry between Wolf and me...
只是一出戏
It was just an act.
一出戏
An act?
我以为《厨房大战》是一档真人秀
I thought that "Kitchen Wars" was a reality show.
强调"秀"  不管输赢
Emphasis on "show." And win or lose,
比赛结束时你都希望人们记住你
you want people to remember your name when it's over.
品牌就是这样建立的
That's how you build your brand.
谁不会记住一位大反派呢
And who doesn't remember a great villain?
没错  我们是为精彩的电视节目作秀
Exactly. Hey, we made for great TV.
不然他们为何留我们到决赛呢
Why do you think they kept us on until the final two?
-但是他赢了  -我个人认为
- But then he won.  - Personally, I was shocked that
你的烘焙猪肚没有胜出真太令人吃惊了
your oven-roasted pork belly glaze didn't take top prize.
-那真是  -我们都是赢家
- That was... just...  - But look, we both won.
没错  伍尔夫得到了自己的餐厅
Yes, Wolf got his own restaurant,
但我的宴会承办公司也得到了财政支持
but I secured financing for a catering company,
生意也不错
and I'm doing great.
如果你没杀他
Well, then if you didn't kill him,
也许你能解释
maybe you can explain
在犯罪现场找到你指纹的原因
why we found your prints at the scene.
导使伍尔夫先生致命的器具上
They were all over the appliance
全是你的指纹
used to bludgeon Mr. Wolf to death.
你说的是旋转蒸发器吗
Are you talking about the rotary evaporator?
有我的指纹是因为那是我的
My prints are on it because it's mine.
我前天借给他的
I loaned it to him the day before yesterday.
他说需要用来制作特色菜品
He said he needed it to make something really special.
等等  他死亡当天你见过他
Wait, you saw him the day he died?
他那天早上打给我  约我见面
He called me early in the morning and asked to meet.
他拿着一个背包吗
Was he carrying a backpack?
是的
Yeah.
他看起来很匆忙  好像是
He seemed in a rush, like he had
有很多事要做却不够时间
a lot of things to do and not a lot of time to do it.
我借给他蒸发器
I gave him the evaporator,
然后他说去市中心见一个人
and then he said he had a meeting in midtown.
他在我回家的路上下车了
He asked me to drop him off on my way home.
那是哪里
And where was that?
47号大街和莱克斯街的东北角
Uh, the Northeast corner of 47th and Lex
一栋写字大楼
One of those big office buildings.
詹妮弗的雇员证实
Jennifer's employees confirm
她在汉普顿有一场承办的宴会
that she had a catering job in the Hamptons
她整晚都在那里
and that she stayed the night.
这很好
Well, just as well.
她的厨艺不会被埋没在监狱厨房了
Her culinary talents would've been wasted in a prison kitchen.
伙计们
Hey, you guys.
去查查这地址的承租人
I need you to check on the tenants at this address.
47号大街东423号
423 East 47th?
显然  伍尔夫死亡当天在那见了某个人
Apparently, Wolf visited someone there the day that he died.
他当时还拿着背包
And he had the backpack with him.
上东区那边进展如何
Hey, how'd things go uptown?
我们盘查了雷克斯咖啡馆的
Well, we talked to every waiter,
所有服务生  打杂工和经理
busboy and manager at Cafe Rex.
他们记得伍尔夫去过  说他总是坐
They remember Wolf coming in and said he sat
前面的那张桌子
at the same table out front,
-但他总是独自一人  -他在那里做什么
- but he was always alone.  - What was he doing?
-喝茶凝望  -有时还会点奶油蛋卷
- Sipping tea, staring.  - Sometimes, he ordered the brioche.
就这样吗  最近两星期天天如此吗
That's it? Every day for the last two weeks?
为什么他去上东区  却独自一人
Why would he go all the way to the upper east side
坐在那里
just to sit there alone?
也许他与命运有约
Maybe he had a rendezvous with destiny,
但被放了鸽子
and it stood him up.
这倒提醒我  你觉得
Which reminds me, what color shirt
麦蒂森喜欢我穿什么颜色的衬衫
do you think Madison would like on me?
和贝克特的老友约会
Going out with Beckett's old friend?
这可是个错误
That's a mistake.
-贝克特好像不介意  -亲爱的
- Oh, Beckett didn't seem to mind.  - Oh, honey.
帮我拿个苹果
Do you want to hand me an apple?
别皱眉了  阿丽克西斯
Stop frowning, Alexis,
不然你爸会把你的脸冻成那样
or your father will freeze your face like that.
他不需要
He doesn't have to.
我刚发现我必须用显微镜观察载玻片
I just found out I have to study slides with a microscope
大学预修化学考试需要
for my AP Chem exam.
我不能带着显微镜去汉普顿
I can't take a microscope to the Hamptons.
你要取消行程吗
Oh, so you're canceling your trip?
当我学习时  我会想和姑娘们一起去沙滩
When I'm studying, I'll want to be on the beach with the girls,
而在沙滩时  我会因为不学习有罪恶感
and when I'm on the beach, I'll feel guilty for not studying.
别看我
Well, don't look at me.
做决定的时候我从来都是"鱼和熊掌兼得"
I'm from the "Have your cake and eat it, too" school
要我说两个都去做
of decision making. I say do both.
或者到这个周末的时候
Or maybe by this weekend,
我可以想出法子把这瓶液氮
I'll figure out a way to take this tank of liquid nitrogen
安装在一个气象机器里
and build it into a weather machine.
我就可以呼风唤雨  你的朋友就得取消行程
I'll make it rain, your friends will have to cancel their trip.
你就不必选了
You won't have to choose,
然后我们就可以称霸全世界
and then we can take over the world!
一点忙都帮不上
Not helpful.
但很邪恶
But evil.
你不是应该去准备你的约会了吗
Shouldn't you be getting ready for your date?
你不是也应该回切特那里吗
Shouldn't you be back home with Chet?
没错  我...
Oh, you're right. I...
我冻结了时间
I froze time.
麦蒂
Maddie?
你看起来漂亮极了
You look amazing.
谢谢  我想给你们这个
Thanks. Hey, I, um... I wanted to drop this off.
为你们所做的一切
It's my way of saying thank you
聊表谢意
for everything you guys are doing.
这是我们的工作
Oh, y-- you know, it's what we do.
但有曲奇吃我们还是很感激的
But we are always very grateful for cookies.
我喜欢燕麦曲奇
I love oatmeal cookies.
很高兴你喜欢
I'm glad.
嘿  小贝
Hey, Becks...
你还记得我们都喜欢的那个
Do you remember when we used to like
英语课上的男孩吗
the same guy in English class?
记得  布伦特·爱德华兹
Yes. Brent Edwards.
他很性感
He was very hot.
是的
Yes.
那你还记得高三那年的事吗
Do you also remember what happened senior year?
是的  为什么
Uh, yeah. Why?
和里克的约会
This date with Rick.
如果你们俩...
If you guys are at all...
卡塞尔  没有
Castle? N-no.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
因为我真的不想
Because I really wouldn't want
再重蹈布伦特·爱德华兹那样的覆辙
Brent Edwards to happen all over again?
相信我  不会的
Trust me. It's not.
好吧  太好了
Okay. Great.
今晚玩得开心点
So have fun tonight.
谢谢  你也是
Thanks. You, too.
嘿
Hey.
嘿  准备好了吗
Hey. Uh, so you ready?
没有  督察刚刚给我下了通牒
No. My lieutenant just brought down the hammer.
五份材料必须在今晚交班时写好
Fives have to be written up before shift end tonight.
-很抱歉  -别
- I'm sorry.  - Uh, no.
我有
Uh, you know, I have--
我也有些文书工作要做
I have, uh, some paperwork to do as well.
也许下次吧
So maybe another time.
但是我今晚一心想约你
Well, the thing is, I kinda had my heart set on tonight.
你喜欢中国菜吗
You like Chinese?
我的最爱
It's my favorite.
太好了  等会
Great. Wait here.
-麦蒂森  节哀顺变  -你好
- Madison, I'm so sorry. - Hi.
太不幸了  伍尔夫是个不错的朋友
It's a tragic loss. Wolf was a good friend.
没错  他很崇拜你
Yeah, he really admired you.
谢谢今晚的光临  这对我意义重大
Thanks for coming tonight. It means a lot to me.
雷克  这位是理查德·卡塞尔先生
Rocco, this is Richard Castle.
卡塞尔  我真想痛扁你的脸
I ought to punch you in the face, Castle...
谁让你杀死德里克·斯道姆
for killing Derrick Storm like that.
他是我最喜爱的小说人物
He was my favorite character.
当然《希特热浪》也很有趣
But I'll admit, "Heat wave" is fun, too.
是以我的朋友凯特·贝克特作为原型的
Based on my friend, Kate Beckett.
我应该介绍你俩认识  你俩准合得来
I should introduce you. You guys might hit it off.
我很乐意
I'd like that.
如果她真人有书中的角色一半有趣
If she's half as interesting in person as she is on the page,
那我早已喜欢上她了
I think I like her already.
-你们尽兴  祝用餐愉快  -谢谢
- Well, you guys have fun. Enjoy your dinner. - Thanks.
一流的主厨
Fabulous chef.
你真的认为他是贝克特喜欢的类型吗
You... you really think he's Beckett's type?
小贝从没有固定喜欢的类型
Well, Becks never had a type.
她约会过垃圾乐队的吉他手
She dated a guitarist in a grunge band,
医学院学生  还有个法国人
a med student and this french guy,
我非常肯定他是皇室成员之类的
but I'm pretty sure he was some kind of royalty.
她现在和谁约会?
Who is she seeing now?
和某人
Oh, just... some guy.
我不看好他们
I don't see it going anywhere.
这顿饭太美味了
This food's amazing.
你从哪买来的
Where did you get it from?
洪记中国海餐厅
Hung's China Sea.
胡说  洪记不送餐上门
Oh, get out. Hung's doesn't deliver.
他会送餐给我
Well, he delivers to me.
洪先生有一块
Mr. Hung had this medal--
源自十五世纪明朝的奖牌
a 15th-century chinese medal, Ming Dynasty.
是家族流传下来的
It was passed down through the generations, right?
去年  这块奖牌连同一些现金
Well, last year it was stolen along with some cash
厨房用具及其它一起被偷了
and some kitchen appliances and whatnot.
对洪先生而言最重要的是那块奖牌
The only thing that mattered to Mr. Hung was the medal.
我把奖牌完璧归赵了
So I got it back for him.
我为他送去奖牌  他为我送来饭菜
And because I delivered, now so does he.
是嘛  那或许我应该找你帮忙查出
Really? Well, then maybe I should get you to figure out
受害人背着一个装满现金背包的原因
why our victim was carrying a backpack full of cash.
那你真应该这样做
Well, maybe you should.
知道吗  我在道上有线人
You know, I got some guys on the street.
如你有需要  我能帮你打听一下
If you want, I can put out feelers,
看看有没有人知道些什么
see if anybody knows anything.
这当然好了
Yeah, sure.
-打扰了  探长们  -伙计们
- Excuse me, detectives. - Hey, guys.
-哇  烛光晚餐  -进来吧
- Wow. Nice candle. - Come on in.
有什么发现
What'd you find?
我们查看了詹妮弗·王送伍尔夫去的
Well, we checked the sign-in log at that building
那栋大厦的访客记录
where Jennifer Wong dropped off Wolf.
他是去见一位名为
Turns out he was seeing a guy named
西蒙·海姆的律师
Simon Haim, esquire.
他把装满现金的背包拿去给一个律师
He was delivering a backpack full of cash to a lawyer?
根据海姆先生的供词
Well, according to Mr. Haim,
伍尔夫的确持有一个背包
Wolf had the backpack in his possession,
但他并没有打开
but he never opened it
也没有提及现金的事
and he never even mentioned the cash.
但他提到了你的高中同学麦蒂森
But he did mention your high school friend Madison.
显然  伍尔夫想取消合同
Apparently, Wolf wanted out of his contract.
他想离开餐厅
He wanted to leave the restaurant,
并且想要退股
and he wanted his investment back.
但餐厅才刚开张
But the restaurant just opened.
他怎会想要离开
Why would he want to leave?
经营理念分歧
Creative differences,
但凯勒小姐不肯放他走
but Ms. Queller refused to release him.
伍尔夫打算提出诉讼
Wolf was planning to sue.
她的餐厅是靠伍尔夫的名声打出名堂的
She'd built the restaurant on his reputation.
他一旦离开  她就会失去一切
If he left, she would've lost everything.
现在伍尔夫死了  Q3归谁
So what happens to Q3 now that Wolf is dead?
她为伍尔夫买了商业保险
She had business insurance on him.
有了这笔赔偿
So with the payout,
麦蒂森就能轻而易举获得整个餐厅
Madison gets the restaurant, free and clear.
伍尔夫的死让她免于在房地产
Wolf's death protects her from potentially
机械与设备上损失二百万美元
losing $2 million in real estate, appliances and fixtures.
听起来像是杀人动机
Sounds like motive to me.
这真是...
This... mmm.
-是吧  -我的天啊
- Right? - Mmm. Oh,my god.
这真是
This is...
这个鱼子酱冻糕味道好极了
This caviar parfait is delicious.
我用意式黑松露脆皮炸虾烩饭
Trade you for some of my black truffle risotto
和你交换
with crispy shrimp.
那真是让我难以拒绝
Oh, well... how could I resist?
那真是
That is...
抱歉打扰了
I'm sorry to interrupt.
-你来了  -贝克特
- Hey. - Beckett.
你在这里做什么
What are you doing here?
我有些问题要问麦蒂森
I-I need to ask Madison a few questions.
行  拉张椅子过来坐
Oh, well, pull up a chair.
这里不行  回警局谈
Not here. Downtown.
当你像个搞笑警察般踏进餐厅  你应该清楚
You realize Madison and I weren't halfway through
我和麦蒂森的试味套餐连一半都没有吃完
our tasting menus when you stomped in there like the fun police?
她是谋杀案的嫌疑人  这件事上
What part of her being a suspect in a murder investigation
你有哪点不懂呢
do you not get?
侍应正要端上
The waiter was about to come out
油封鸭[法国名菜]
with the duck confit en croute,
雷克·迪斯普利托的南瓜土豆粉团
Rocco Dispirito's pumpkin gnocchi,
更甭提之后要上的海螯虾
not to mention the langoustine,
和薰衣草味焦糖布蕾了
the lavender creme brulee that was coming up.
更过分就是我连配餐红酒都没喝上
And don't even get me started on the wine pairings.
了解了
I won't.
我是说  你可以表现得更礼貌些
I'm just saying, you could've been more civilized
让我们先把晚餐吃完
and allowed us to finish our meal.
你可以在观察室里看
You can watch from the observation room.
你现在竟然让我去场外坐冷板凳
And now...and now you're benching me?
你刚还在跟我们的嫌疑人吃饭嬉笑
You were just giggling over the risotto with our suspect.
顺便一提  那是梦寐以求的意式烩饭
Which was to die for, by the way.
够了  下次当我勾搭了你喜欢的人
Okay. Next time I'm hitting on a guy you like,
请在我和他出去前跟我挑明
come clean with me before I go out with him,
那你就不必逮捕我来破坏约会
so you don't have to arrest me to break up the date.
麦蒂森  不是那样的
Madison, that's not--
不  我明白  你为卡塞尔着迷
No, no, no, no, no. I get it. You're hot for Castle.
你想为他生小卡塞尔
You want to make little Castle babies.
-为什么你就不能诚实点呢  -麦蒂
- Why couldn't you just be honest? - Maddie.
-又怎么了  -他能听到我们说话
- What? - He can hear us.
-真的吗  -真的
- Oh, really? - Yes.
-里克在镜子后面  -没错
- Rick's behind the mirror? - Yeah.
就像电视演的那样吗
Oh. Like on TV?
那边的  可惜我们错过了南瓜土豆粉团
Hey there! Sorry we missed the pumpkin gnocchi.
那真的很好吃
They're really good.
我要把这事写上微博
I have to tweet about this.
麦蒂森  把电话放下
Madison, put the phone down.
坐下
Sit.
你对我撒谎了  你知道
You lied to me. You knew that
伍尔夫想离开Q3
Wolf wanted out of Q3,
也知道他打算起诉你
and you knew that he was gonna sue you.
你都知道了
You know about that?
是的  我都知道
Yeah, I know about that.
好吧  但我没说谎
Okay, but I didn't lie.
只是隐瞒了此事
I just neglected to say anything about it.
你知道在曼哈顿开一间餐厅有多难吗
Okay, you know how hard it is to open a restaurant in Manhattan?
如果伍尔夫想退出的消息传出去
If word got out that Wolf was trying to leave,
我就完蛋了
it would've ruined me.
但是只要他死了
But if he dies,
靠着保险赔偿金  你就能应付自如
with your insurance policy, you make out just fine.
麦蒂  发生了什么  你们动手了吗
So what happened, Maddie? Did you guys get into a fight?
你向他扔东西了吗
Did you throw something at him?
因为我记得你生气时
Because I remember you throwing things at people
总喜欢向人扔东西
when you got angry.
拜托
Oh, come on.
你们应该不允许用个人所知
Don't you people have rules
去指控嫌疑人
about using personal knowledge against suspects?
麦蒂  你最好现在向我坦白
Maddie, you better start being straight with me.
小贝  我没杀他
Becks, I didn't kill him.
两个星期前
Two weeks ago,
伍尔夫无缘无故说
Wolf tells me he wants out of the restaurant biz,
要退出餐厅的生意
completely out of nowhere.
他说想改变自己的生活
Says he's trying to change his life.
我当时以为他是被挖角了
Now I'm thinking he's being poached.
所以我开始为他提供更好的设备
So I start offering better equipment,
更多的分红  他想要的一切
a bigger piece in the business, whatever he wants.
但他坚持他真是要离开
He insists he's really getting out
我无法动摇他
and that I can't change his mind.
就像是他的人生发生了重大变化
It was like something changed in his life.
我正准备跟他解约
Now I was gonna let him out of his contract.
我只是需要时间找个新主厨
I just needed time to find a new chef.
但我发誓  小贝  我没杀他
But I swear, Becks, I didn't kill him.
你不会真认为是她干的吧
You don't really think she did it, do you?
在她排除嫌疑之前
Well, until I can rule her out,
我怎么想不重要
it doesn't matter what I think.
-她有作案动机  -但也有不在场证明
- She has motive.  - Yeah, she also has an alibi,
你却一直忽视这个事实
which you're conveniently ignoring.
我没有忽视  我是在核实
I'm not ignoring. I'm just rechecking.
我让她无论如何都别离开
I asked her to stay in town in any case.
是  我知道  我听到了
Yes, I know. I heard...
每一句话
everything.
他卖掉了餐馆的股份
So, uh, selling his stake in the restaurant,
带着一个装满现金的背包
a backpack full of cash...
伍尔夫像是
That sounds like Wolf was
-准备要逃跑  -没错  但为什么逃呢
- getting ready to run.  - Yes, but from what?
-嘿  你们好  -嘿
- Hey, you guys.  - Hey.
-抱歉刚才中途放你鸽子  -没事
- I'm so sorry to cut out on you earlier.  - No worries.
-正好给我时间打听被害人的消息  -怎样
- It gave me time to put the word out on your vic.  - And?
我认识一个家伙  替本地庄家做文书工作
Well, a guy I know runs paper for a local bookmaking ring.
没想到他还是个美食家
Turns out he's a bit of a foodie.
他认出伍尔夫  在双桥酒吧找庄家下注
He clocked Wolf doing business with a bookie at Two Bridges Bar.
显然  被害人很喜欢赌大的
Apparently, your boy likes to bet big.
他和庄家有纠葛
He was in deep with a bookie.
这就解释了殴打伤痕和现金
That explains the beating and the cash.
你知道庄家的名字吗
Does this bookie have a name?
韦斯利·斯雷德
Wesley Slade?
我是贝克特探长  纽约警察局的
Detective Beckett, NYPD.
我们在调查巴尔萨扎·伍尔夫的谋杀案
We're investigating the murder of Balthazar Wolf.
不认识他
Never heard of him.
是吗  你手下把他打的
Really? Well, given the marks on his body
满身伤痕  我认为
after the beating your boys gave him,
-你肯定认识  -怎么回事
- I think you have.  - What happened?
他欠债太多  所以你要他偿命
He get in too deep with you, so you had to take him out?
我不会跟个条子讲我的生意往来的
You really think I'm gonna tell my business to a cop?
要么交待  要么等着谋杀的指控吧
It's either that or you face murder charges.
那可对你的生意不利
That can't be good for business.
好吧
All right.
就假设说  他找我下注
Let's say, hypothetically, that I made book for him.
考虑到也有可能  他欠我很多钱
And let's say for the sake of argument that he owed me a lot.
-假设说  欠多少  -两万五
- How much, hypothetically? - 25 thou,
他可能还不了
which maybe he couldn't pay.
所以他可能需要一点"激励"
So maybe he needed some encouragement.
可能"激励"的太过了点
Maybe the encouragement went too far.
也有可能恰到好处
Or maybe it was the right amount.
所以他才能还了钱  走上幸福大道
So he paid what he owed and went his merry way.
什么时候
When?
他死的那天  带着一背包现金来
The day he died, he comes in with a backpack full of cash,
放了两万五到桌子上  要回了他的戒指
puts 25 thou on the table and asks for his ring back.
戒指  什么样的戒指
His ring? What kind of ring?
订婚钻戒
Diamond engagement ring.
怎么在你手上
Why'd you have it?
假设的说
Hypothetically.
两星期前  我派手下去收钱
Couple of weeks back, I sent my guys to collect, didn't
他没钱  讲了他和某个女人的烂故事
have the money, gave some sob story about a woman,
说他花光所有积蓄买了个钻戒
how he spent everything he had on a diamond ring.
当我手下准备"激励"他一下的时候
So when my guys go to give him some... encouragement,
猜猜发现了什么  一枚漂亮的钻戒
Oh, what do they find? A nice diamond ring.
很大颗  够抵一万  甚至一万五的欠债
Nice. Must have set him back 10, 15 grand... of my money.
于是你的手下就拿了那个当抵押
So your guys took it for collateral?
不  是当作还钱的动机
No, as incentive.
效果不错
And it worked.
我拿到了钱  他拿回了戒指
I got my money, he got his ring,
他是活着回去的  假设的说
and he goes home alive... hypothetically.
订婚钻戒完全能解释这一切
An engagement ring makes perfect sense.
他和迈尔斯太太分手
That's why he broke things off with Mrs. Meyers.
两星期前他从帐户里取了一万五千美元
That's why he took $15,000 out of his account 2 weeks ago.
那戒指在哪里呢
Well, then where is it?
他拿到戒指就回餐厅了
He went to the restaurant right after,
在犯罪现场我们也没找到
and we didn't find it at the crime scene.
也许我们找到了  只是不知道而已
Unless we did find it and we just didn't know it.
径直往后走
Just straight back.
谢谢  记得斯派克说伍尔夫
Thank you. You remember what Spike was saying
迟迟没走的原因吗
about why Wolf was staying late?
记得  他在做那个蛋糕
Yeah, he was finishing off that cake.
一个
A cake...
带心形模型的蛋糕
with a heart-shaped mold on it.
他不是打算逃跑
He wasn't running away.
而是准备求婚
He was going to propose.
向谁求婚呢
But to who?
而且她为何还没出现呢
And why hasn't she come forward yet?
她可能是害怕  可能她正面临危险
Maybe she's scared. Maybe she's in danger.
还可能是她杀了他
Or maybe she killed him.
谁会把订婚戒指放蛋糕里面
Who puts an engagement ring inside a cake?
很浪漫啊
It's romantic.
得了吧  那会噎死人的
Oh, pl-- it's a choking hazard.
我敢说  男人求婚时总做些奇怪的事
I swear, men act as though there's some cosmic reward
以为会有超级大奖等着
for crazy proposals.
而一个女人要的只是
And what a woman really wants is
男人单膝跪地
a man down on one knee,
双眼含泪  手捧钻戒
tears in his eyes, ring in his hand.
我对吉娜的求婚非常浪漫
My proposal to Gina was very romantic.
热气球升空是不错  但不该在二月
A balloon ride is lovely, but not in February.
因为寒冷  她的手的确抖个不停
Her hand was shaking so much from the cold,
-连戒指都戴不上  -那是个预兆
- it was difficult getting that ring on.  - It was a sign.
你决定了没
So have you decided?
没
No.
大卫  再次为你失去亲人深表遗憾
Again, David, I'm sorry for your loss.
有发现没
Shed any light?
大卫说要不是我把戒指给他看
So David said that he wouldn't have believed it
他都不会相信
unless I'd shown him the ring.
他不知道伍尔夫要向谁求婚
He had no idea who Wolf was proposing to,
他身边的其他人也不知道
and neither did anyone else in his life.
就像他在和鬼魂恋爱一样
It's like the guy was in love with a ghost.
如果真是鬼魂的话  就太酷了
Ooh, that'd be cool, if it was actually a ghost.
重新查看了餐厅和
Went back through the phone logs
伍尔夫手机的电话记录
from the restaurant and Wolf's cell.
每通电话都事出有因
Every call's accounted for.
那上东区的咖啡馆情况如何
What about the cafe uptown?
所有的员工都询问过了
The waitstaff all checked out.
他们肯定伍尔夫从未见过任何人
They're adamant that Wolf never met anybody there.
怎么可能不留任何痕迹的
How do you have a relationship with somebody
和别人展开恋情呢
without leaving any evidence?
可能那不是他的戒指
Maybe the ring wasn't his.
也许他只是替某个朋友保管着
Maybe he was holding it for a friend.
不  肯定是他的  想想他的行为
No, it had to be his. Look at his behavior--
他不再四处鬼混  还了债款
He stops sleeping around, he was paying off his debts,
他卖掉了生命中唯一在乎的东西
he sold the one thing in life he actually cared about
就为了换回那枚戒指
just to get that ring back.
只有一个原因能让男人悔过自新
There's only one reason a man cleans up his act.
但用谋杀来回应求婚不合常理
Yeah, but murder isn't the usual response to a proposal.
除非那女人怕失去已有的身边人
Unless you got something to lose.
他的确喜欢已婚妇女
He did like married women.
好  让鉴证组重新检查他的公寓
All right. Have CSU resweep his apartment.
若那个女孩在那里待过
If this girl spent any time there,
肯定会留下一些痕迹
she must have left some evidence behind.
嘿  麦蒂  感谢你赶来
Hey, Maddie. Thanks for coming.
你不是说我已排除嫌疑了吗
I thought you said I was off the hook.
是的  有证人看到你
Yeah, uh, witnesses have you
在被害者死前一直待在聚会上
at the party until after the time of death.
那还叫我来干什么
Then why am I here?
有人给过你这个吗
Anyone ever offered you one of these?
没有  你呢
No. You?
还没有
Not yet.
我都不知道伍尔夫会对谁动真情
I had no idea Wolf was even serious with anyone.
你记得他和谁走的比较近吗
Can you think of any girl that he was close to?
每次看到他  身边都是不同的人
Every time I saw him, he was with someone different.
很难相信他会对谁许下承诺
It's hard to believe he'd ever commit.
那家伙全天候的工作  肯定是
The guy lived his job 24/7. It had to be somebody
-餐厅里的某个人  -不一定
- at the restaurant.  - Not necessarily.
我曾经喜欢过地铁里某个陌生女人
I've fallen in love with random women on the subway.
如果你想到了谁  给我打电话
Well, if you can think of anyone, call me.
好  还有  小贝
Yeah. And, Becks...
对不起
I'm sorry...
我不该撒谎
about lying to you.
我办案手法可能也
And I might have come down
有点过于强硬了
a little harder than I needed to.
我曾经一度十分爱慕接线员
I've fallen I love with operators on the phone.
几年前  还打算约一位见面
Even asked one out a couple of years ago,
可是她却身在孟加拉国
but she was in Bangladesh.
也许是因为我没把你看做警察
Yeah, I guess I wasn't seeing you as a cop,
而是看作我的朋友  看作是那个
but as my friend-- you know, the girl
偷妈妈的化妆品给我化妆的女孩
who stole her mom's makeup to give me a makeover.
第一个告诉我
The first who told me
和男孩接吻时  舌头也要参与其中的女孩
that kissing boys might involve some tongue.
是的
Oh, yeah.
我曾接连两个月都去买炸豆泥三明治
I bought a falafel from this stand every day for two months
只为了和卖三明治的女孩说上几句
just so I could talk to the falafel girl.
再比如说戴明每天早晨都跑来
Yeah, you mean like Demming showing up
喝咖啡  就是为了能见到贝克特
every morning for coffee just to run into Beckett?
想到什么了
What?
同样是那个女孩拖着我
The one who dragged me
站在布伦特·爱德华兹的豪宅外几个小时
to stand outside Brent Edwards' brownstone for hours
就是为了能透过窗户看他一眼
on end just to catch a glimpse of him through the window.
透过窗户
Through the window.
伍尔夫不是去雷克斯咖啡馆见他的女友
Wolf wasn't going to Cafe Rex to meet his girl.
而是透过咖啡馆的玻璃窗看她
He was watching her out the cafe window.
这就解释了为什么没有电话记录
That's why there were no phone calls.
他在鼓起勇气向她求婚
He was trying to gather up the courage to propose to her.
这就是从咖啡馆  看得最清楚的店铺
So that's the store with the clearest view from the cafe.
要么我们的神秘女孩在这里工作
Well, either our mystery girl works here,
要么就是伍尔夫对女式服装很着迷
or Wolf was really into women's clothes.
也许是他
Maybe it's him.
也许那就是伍尔夫的秘友
Maybe that's Wolf's big secret.
那人不会是他的秘友
That's not his secret.
她才是
She is.
那是他义兄的女友
That's his foster brother's girlfriend.
不错
Yep.
这的确会让求婚变得比较棘手
Well, it definitely made proposing tricky.
我不明白  我为什么会被带到这
I don't understand. Why am I here?
你和伍尔夫关系如何  茜茜莉
How well did you know Wolf, Cecily?
他就像家人一样
He was like family.
就是说你认识他很长时间了
So you knew him for a long time.
十年了  自从大卫的爸爸雇我
Well, ten years, ever since David's father
在他的餐馆工作开始
hired me at his restaurant.
你们有没有过...
Did the two of you ever...
为什么问我这个
Why are you asking me this?
最近的两个星期
Every day for the last two weeks,
伍尔夫一直去雷克斯咖啡馆
Wolf went to Cafe Rex,
就在你工作店铺的马路对面
which is right across the street from where you work.
他只是坐在那里  看着窗外
He would just sit there and look out the window.
在看你
Looking at you.
他为什么这么做
Now why would he do that?
-我不知道  -我认为你知道
- I don't know.  - I think you do.
在最近的两周里  伍尔夫做了很多改变
In the last two weeks, Wolf made a lot of changes.
不再到处鬼混  偿还了债务
He'd stopped sleeping around, paid off all his debts...
而且给你买了这个
And he bought this... for you.
是什么使一个十年间
What makes a man-- a self-professed bad boy--
臭名昭著的坏小子突然转变了呢
Suddenly declare himself after ten years?
除非有什么事发生了
Unless something changed.
茜茜莉  这些是你的电话记录
Cecily, these are your phone records.
四个月前  你开始定期打电话给妇产科医生
Four months ago, you started calling your ob/gyn regularly.
你怀孕了  是伍尔夫的孩子  对吗
You're pregnant. It's Wolf's, isn't it?
原以为没人会知道
No one was supposed to know.
这是我的秘密
It was supposed to be my secret.
但是当大卫告诉伍尔夫我怀孕了
But when David told Wolf we were pregnant,
他不知怎么就明白了
Somehow he knew.
他就...明白了
He... he knew.
上帝  你一定认为我糟糕透了
God, you must think I'm awful.
我无法评判  但我旨在寻求真相
It's not my job to judge. I'm just here to get the truth.
大卫的父亲去世了
David's father had just died,
所以他离开这里
so David went out of the country
去家乡安葬他的父亲
to bury his father in his hometown.
伍尔夫过来了
Wolf came by.
他握着我的手  我想起...
He held my hand, and I remembered...
我是多么的爱他  一直深爱着他
How much I loved him, that I'd always loved him.
既然爱他  为什么和大卫在一起
If you loved him so much, why stay with David?
因为大卫不会丢下我
Because David doesn't leave.
大卫不会和遇见的每个女孩都上床
David doesn't sleep with every girl who walks by.
你不会明白
You have no idea how hard it is
爱一个明知会让你心碎的男人是多么辛苦
to love someone, knowing they're gonna break your heart.
如果我无法相信他是个好男人
If I couldn't trust him as a man,
又怎能相信他会是个好父亲
how could he be a father?
我得做出选择
I had to make a choice.
上帝啊  别让大卫知道
Oh, god. Please don't tell David.
你确定他还不知道吗
Are you sure he doesn't already know?
伍尔夫被谋杀的当晚  他在哪
Where was he the night that Wolf was murdered?
家里...  和我躺在床上
At home... with me in bed.
整晚
All night?
老天
Oh, god.
怎么了
What?
我一直都有睡眠问题
I had been having trouble sleeping.
所以大卫给了我安眠药
So David gave me a pill,
是那种医生说很安全的
the kind the doctor said was okay.
他只有那晚给了我安眠药
It was the only time he's ever given me a pill.
伙计  带他去拘留所
Hey, man. Take him to the hole, please?
把他关起来  我们待会儿过去
Yeah, lock him up. We'll be right over.
我们走
Come on. Let's go.
-他什么也不说  -是的  也无须说什么
- He's not talking.  - Yeah, but he didn't have to.
在他们的公寓里找到了伍尔夫的背包
We found Wolf's backpack in their apartment
还有剩下的那些现金
along with the extra cash.
还发现了他的一双鞋子
We also found a pair of his shoes
鞋底因沾上液氮裂开了
with cracked soles from the liquid nitrogen.
无法想象被兄弟背叛的感觉
I can't imagine the betrayal he must have felt.
这不是杀人的借口
It's still not an excuse to kill.
要我说...
You ask me...
她应该听从心声
She should've followed her heart--
离开大卫  和伍尔夫在一起
Left David, gone with Wolf.
我能理解留在大卫身边所体现的原则
You know, I can see the virtue in staying.
我意思是  像伍尔夫这类人  凭空出现
I mean, guys like Wolf, they come in,
扰乱你的生活步骤
they upset the apple cart.
当然也会使你觉得生机勃勃
Of course he makes you feel alive,
但最终你会明白  他只会让你失望
but eventually, you know he's just gonna let you down.
所以干嘛冒险呢
So why risk it?
因为情之所系  心之所在
Because the heart wants what the heart wants.
说到这
Speaking of...
我该走了
I gotta get outta here.
-约了麦蒂森吗  -不是  最近发生的事情太多
- Madison? - No. Actually, with everything going on,
她说没时间约会了
She said she didn't have time to date.
她没和你说吗
She didn't tell you that?
我得回家了
So I gotta get home.
阿丽克西斯被同样的问题困扰着
Alexis has a little head-heart problem of her own,
她拿主意时我要在一旁支持她
and I want to be there for the decision.
结案了吗
Case closed?
是的
Yes.
感谢你的帮助
Thank you so much for all of your help.
愿意效劳
Anytime. But, you know,
但我们的晚餐始终没有吃完
we never really finished our dinner.
报告都写完了
No more fives.
想去雷米餐馆喝瓶啤酒  吃个汉堡吗
You want to grab a beer and a burger at Remy's?
我很想去  只是...
You know, I would love to, it's, just, uh...
可以改天吗
Can I take a rain check?
你是要去什么地方吗
Somewhere else you need to be?
是的
Yeah.
明天怎么样
How about tomorrow?
好啊  一言为定
Yeah. You're on.
好的
Okay.
你决定了  周末和朋友们出去
You decided to go away for the weekend with your friends.
她们一小时后来接我
They're picking me up in an hour.
-听起来这个决定并没有让你高兴  -没有
- You don't sound thrilled with your decision. - I'm not.
感觉糟透了  但不管怎样  都是一样的
I feel awful about it, but either way, it's the same.
有什么我可以做的
Well, is there anything I can do
使你感觉好一点
to make it easier on you?
有
Yes.
-你可以命令我待在家里  -你是认真的
- You can order me to stay home.  - Y-you're serious?
好吧
All right.
阿丽克西斯  你的大学预修考试要比
Alexis, your AP Exams are far too important
周末和你的朋友们
for you to go gallivanting around the weekend
在海滩闲逛重要得多
with your friends at the beach.
我坚持认为你得待在家里温习
You have to stay home and study. I insist.
我得打给蕾西
Oh, I gotta call Lacey.
蕾西  我很抱歉
Lacey. Yeah, I'm so sorry.
可我老爸不让我去
But my dad just told me I can't go.
我得周末待在家里为考试温习
I have to stay home and study for exams this weekend.
是的  我知道  你能相信吗
Yeah, I know. I know. Can you believe it?
-是的  再也不是什么好老爸了  -闺女
- Yeah, so much for having a cool dad. - Dude--
抱歉了
Well, I'm sorry.
照一大堆照片  发过来给我看
And just take lots of pictures and text 'em to me.
好  再见
Okay. Bye.
谢谢
Thank you.
当你看到周末我准备了什么
You won't be thanking me when you see
你就不会谢我了
what I have planned for this weekend.
有1001个方法干扰人们学习
1,001 ways to distract someone who's studying.
就以冰镇乒乓球开始吧
We start by freezing ping-pong balls.
好了  伙计们  时刻铭记要干练
Okay, guys, let's remember to be sharp,
谦恭  还有留心  好吗
respectful and attentive. Okay?
享受今晚
Have a good night.
-嘿  又开张了  -是的
- Hey, you're reopening.  - Yes.
我找到了替代伍尔夫的合适人选
I found a hot new chef to step into Wolf's shoes.
-那太好了  -确实
- Oh, that's so great.  - Yeah.
你好  探长  不会再审我一番吧
Hello, Detective. You're not here to question me again?
不会  以朋友的身份来的
No, I'm just here as a friend.
-祝贺你  -谢谢
- Congratulations.  - Thank you.
是大卫杀了伍尔夫
So David killed Wolf?
是的  他看到了一条伍尔夫给茜茜莉的
Yeah. It turns out that he intercepted a text
询问关于腹中宝宝的短信
that Wolf sent Cecily asking about the baby.
起初  他打算找茜茜莉谈这件事的
And at first, he was gonna approach Cecily about it
可他意识到只要伍尔夫还活着
until he realized that eventually she would leave him
她最终会选择离开
as long as Wolf was alive.
该隐与亚伯重现[圣经故事  兄杀弟]
Wow. Very Kane and Abel.
是啊  看来你还是很忙碌啊
Yeah. So I take it that you're swamped.
是啊  有事吗
Always. Why?
我本打算和你喝一杯  叙叙旧
I thought that we could get a drink and catch up.
很不错啊
That'd be great.
显然  我们有很多可聊的
Apparently, we have a lot of catching up to do.